Arvind Laxminarayan

Bengaluru

+919986415384 ardsrk@gmail.com

Objective

To work in a technically strong team. Especially leveraging open source tools and technologies.

Summary

Software developer with over eight years experience. I am interested in applying my skills to develop applications that are useful to people in their daily lives.

With experience I have learned to use the software tools effectively to get work done. It has also taught me the value of collaboration and interaction with people.

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Cleartrip Pvt. Ltd

April 2012 – Present

Designed and developed many value added services (like the automated web check-in to reserve preferred flight seats) for travellers.

Ruby Programmer

99tests Pvt. Ltd

July 2011 - March 2012

Development and maintenance of **99tests**, a crowdsourced software testing platform.

Ruby Programmer

C42 Engineering

October 2010 – April 2011

Responsible for development of Ruby On Rails applications for multiple clients. Applications were developed using Agile methodologies like pair programming, and test-driven development.

Software Engineer

Geodesic Ltd

March 2008 – June 2010

Responsible for development of mobile applications like multi-protocol chat, and Internet Radio client for Nokia Symbia S60 phones written in Symbian C++.

Consultant

Capgemini India Pvt Ltd.

August 2006 – November 2007

Responsible for maintenance of a schedule and resource management application hosted on a mainframe computer.

Skills

- Programming languages in decreasing order or proficiency:
 - Ruby
 - SQL
 - C
 - C++
 - Javascript
- Object Oriented Development.
- Linux (Ubuntu).
- Proficient user Vim editor.
- Proficient user of Git version control system.
- Good written and spoken communication skills in English.

Education

B.E. Computer Science

October 2002 - June 2006

Dayananda Sagar College Of Engineering, Bengaluru.

Interests

In my spare time I like to contribute to open source software. I have made minor contributions to <u>GNU Wget</u> and <u>Redis</u> key-value store.

I also like to read books. Below is a sample list of books I have enjoyed reading:

- Understanding Computation: From simple machines to impossible programs, by Tom Stuart.
- Refactoring: Improving the design of existing code, by Martin Fowler.
- Programming Pearls, 2nd Edition, by Jon Bentley.
- The Art Of Unix Programming, by Eric Raymond.
- Effective C++, 3rd Edition, by Scott Meyers.